# **Brandon Amos**

**☎** (540) 947 1238 • ⊠ bamos@cs.cmu.edu • 🕆 bamos.github.io in bdamos ● ♥ brandondamos ● ♠ bamos Generated on November 2, 2016

I am a third-year Computer Science Ph.D. student at Carnegie Mellon University and am supported by an NSF graduate research fellowship. I spent the first two years of my Ph.D. working between mobile computing and applied machine learning and I now work with Zico Kolter on machine learning and optimization. I am particularly interested in improving our understanding of important modeling problems in computer vision, language, and reinforcement learning through the use of deep learning, optimization (sometimes convex), theory, and statistics.

As an example, we've recently been exploring the intersection of deep learning and convex optimization with input convex neural networks (ICNNs): neural networks that are convex with respect to some of the inputs. Our preprint is available at arXiv:1609.07152 and shows applications to multi-label classification, image completion, and continuous-action reinforcement learning.

I strongly believe in open science and reproducible research and actively publish code on my Github profile. I am also the author of OpenFace, which is an open source face recognition project that uses deep learning.

## **Education**

<ul> <li>Ph.D. in Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University</li> <li>M.S. in Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University</li> <li>B.S. in Computer Science, Virginia Tech (3.99/4.00)</li> <li>Northside High School (Roanoke, Virginia)</li> </ul>	Aug 2014 - Present Aug 2014 - May 2016 Aug 2011 - May 2014 May 2011
Research Experience	
<ul> <li>Carnegie Mellon University, Prof. Zico Kolter</li> <li>Machine learning and optimization</li> </ul>	Apr 2016 – Present
<ul> <li>Carnegie Mellon University, Prof. Mahadev Satyanarayanan</li> <li>Applied machine learning and mobile computing</li> </ul>	Aug 2014 – Apr 2016
<ul><li>Virginia Tech, Prof. Jules White</li><li>Mobile computing, cyber-physical systems, and security</li></ul>	May 2012 – May 2014
<ul> <li>Virginia Tech, Prof. Layne Watson</li> <li>Scientific computing, global/stochastic optimization, and bioinform</li> </ul>	Jan 2013 – May 2014 atics
<ul><li>Virginia Tech, Prof. Binoy Ravindran</li><li>Heterogeneous compilers</li></ul>	Nov 2012 – Mar 2014

#### **Selected Publications**

- [1] **B. Amos**, L. Xu, J. Z. Kolter, "Input convex neural networks," *ArXiv preprint arXiv:1609.07152*, 2016. [Online]. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/1609.07152.
- [2] H. Zhao, T. Adel, G. Gordon, **B. Amos**, "Collapsed Variational Inference for Sum-Product Networks," in *ICML*, 2016. [Online]. Available: http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~hzhao1/papers/ICML2016/BL-SPN-main.pdf.
- [3] **B. Amos**, B. Ludwiczuk, M. Satyanarayanan, "Openface: A general-purpose face recognition library with mobile applications," Technical Report CMU-CS-16-118, CMU School of Computer Science, Tech. Rep., 2016. [Online]. Available: http://reports-archive.adm.cs.cmu.edu/anon/anon/2016/CMU-CS-16-118.pdf.
- [4] **B. Amos**, D. Easterling, L. Watson, W. Thacker, B. Castle, M. Trosset, "QNSTOP-QuasiNewton Algorithm for Stochastic Optimization," 2014. [Online]. Available: https://vtechworks.lib.vt.edu/bitstream/handle/10919/49672/qnTOMS14.pdf.

#### **Teaching Experience**

<ul> <li>Distributed Systems (CMU 15-440/640), TA</li> </ul>	S2016
<ul> <li>Software Design and Data Structures (VT CS 2114), TA</li> </ul>	S2013

## **Industry Experience**

Data Scientist Intern, Adobe Research	May 2014 – Aug 2014
<ul> <li>Software Engineer Intern, Snowplow Analytics</li> </ul>	Dec 2013 – Jan 2014
<ul> <li>Software Engineer Intern, Qualcomm</li> </ul>	May 2013 – Aug 2013
<ul> <li>Software Engineer Intern, Phoenix Integration</li> </ul>	May 2012 – Aug 2012
<ul> <li>Network Administrator Intern, Sunapsys</li> </ul>	Jan 2011 – Aug 2011

#### **CMU Graduate Coursework**

<ul> <li>Advanced Machine Learning (10-715, Au), B. Poczos</li> </ul>	F2016
o Intermediate Statistics (10-705, Au), L. Wasserman	F2016
o Topics in Deep Learning (10-807), R. Salakhutdinov	F2016
o Machine Learning (10-701, Au), T. Mitchell	S2016
o Computer Vision (16-720, Au), D. Ramanan	S2016
o Convex Optimization (10-725), R. J. Tibshirani	F2015
o Algorithms in the Real World (15-853), G. Blelloch and A. Gupta	F2015
<ul> <li>Semantics of Programming Languages (15-812), A. Platzer</li> </ul>	S2015
Optimizing Compilers for Modern Architecture (15-745), T. Mowry	S2015
<ul> <li>Advanced Operating and Distributed Systems (15-712), D. Andersen</li> </ul>	F2014
o Mobile and Pervasive Computing (15-812), M. Satyanarayanan and D. Siewiorek	F2014

#### **Honors & Awards**

0	NSF Graduate Research Fellowship	2016 – 2019
0	1st Place Undergraduate Senior Capstone Award, Virginia Tech Computer Science	e 2014
0	David Heilman Research Award, Virginia Tech Computer Science	2014
0	Senior Scholar Award, Virginia Tech Computer Science	2014
0	Honorable Mention, CRA Outstanding Undergraduate Researcher Award	2014
0	Awarded eight undergraduate merit scholarships	2011 – 2014

## Skills

Languages Bash, C, C++, CSS, Fortran, Haskell, HTML, Java, JavaScript, LATEX, Lua,

Make, Mathematica, Python, R, Scala

Frameworks Akka, Android SDK/NDK, Caffe, Node.js, NumPy, TensorFlow, Torch7, Pandas,

SciPy, scikit-learn, Spark, Spray

Systems Linux, OSX